<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Blog Title</title><link>https://heninswift.github.io/heninma.github.io</link><description>Blog description</description><copyright>Blog Title</copyright><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><image><url>https://github.githubassets.com/favicons/favicon.svg</url><title>avatar</title><link>https://heninswift.github.io/heninma.github.io</link></image><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 02:27:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><managingEditor>Blog Title</managingEditor><ttl>60</ttl><webMaster>Blog Title</webMaster><item><title>Report by COPU Honorary Chairman Lu Shouqun at the 20th Open Source China Open Source World Conference</title><link>https://heninswift.github.io/heninma.github.io/post/Report%20by%20COPU%20Honorary%20Chairman%20Lu%20Shouqun%20at%20the%2020th%20Open%20Source%20China%20Open%20Source%20World%20Conference.html</link><description>
Co-build an open source ecosystem in the era of artificial intelligence 
Co-build artificial intelligence based on open source 
(open source innovation, digital transformation and intelligent reconstruction)
(Report by COPU Honorary Chairman Lu Shouqun at the 20th Open Source China Open Source World Conference)

1. Huawei has achieved comprehensive and significant results in the R&amp;D of 5G communications, smartphone operating systems (using self-made and domestically collaborated high-performance chips: 7nm/5nm), computing power (single-chip and integrated computing power), and generative large language models. Huawei's Ascend 910B chip has a performance of 376 TFLOPS, close to NVIDIA's A100 level, while the 910C offers 60% of the H100's computing power, but with 40% higher power consumption than the H100. Huawei's executive director Zhang Pingan stated: 'Huawei's innovation direction does not focus on the manufacturing process of a single chip but on innovative system architecture for chips, fully utilizing the advantages of bandwidth and energy.' NVIDIA CEO Jensen Huang said that Huawei is NVIDIA's strongest challenger. Huawei's Cloud Matrix 384 computing cluster solution (using 384 910C chips) improves cluster efficiency by 67% through high-speed bus interconnection and memory pooling, delivering a computing power of 300 PFLOPS, which is twice that of NVIDIA's GB200NVL72 system. Recently, during a conversation with reporters from the People's Daily, Huawei founder Ren Zhengfei mentioned that the U.S. has exaggerated Huawei's achievements, and Huawei is not that powerful yet, asserting that they must strive to reach that level. Our single chip still lags behind the U.S. by one generation; we use mathematics to supplement physics, non-Moore to supplement Moore, and collective computing to complement single chips, achieving practical results.

2. A batch of high-quality generative autoregressive language models has emerged. ① The Tongyi Qianwen Qwen3 mixed reasoning open-source large model developed by Alibaba's MoDa community features its flagship model Qwen3-235B-A22B along with 8 other large models, whose performance has temporarily surpassed DeepSeekR1 and OpenAIo1, officially reaching the top of the global open-source large model throne! ② The Xiaomi MiMo reasoning open-source large model, in the realm of lower parameters, MiMo-7B has surpassed OpenAIo1-mini and Alibaba's Qwen reasoning model QwQ-32B-Preview, showcasing its potential as a leading starting model in the industry for reinforcement learning.

3. The Super Agent CO-Sight developed by ZTE Corporation has topped the international authority Agent GAIA benchmark test, outperforming the four international giants: Google's DeepMind Langfun Agent, Microsoft (+OpenAI) Aworld, MIT's Infant Agent, and Meta's OWL-Workforce, ranking first! It has sparked the next wave of AI (the 'World Model').


4. The sixth generation semiconductor display's ultra-high pixel frontier technology and production line was developed by BOE, featuring ultra-high pixel density (2.24 inches with 1700 pixels), breaking existing strongholds, and establishing the world's most advanced sixth generation new semiconductor display device production line with mass production capabilities. 

5. COPU organized a dozen companies to develop AIOS. AIOS comes in two types: ① one that starts with applications to integrate intelligent modules into the OS, and ② one that starts with architecture or kernel to develop fully intelligent AIOS.


共建人工智能时代的开源生态
共建基于开源的人工智能
（开源创新，数字化转型与智能化重构）
（COPU名誉主席陆首群在第二十届开源中国开源世界大会上报告）

一、华为，在5G通信，智能手机操作系统（采用自制及国内协作的高性能芯片：7nm/5nm），算力（单芯片和算力集成），生成式语言大模型等的研发方面，均取得了全面、重大的成果华为昇腾芯片910B=376TFLOPS接近英伟达A100水平，910C为H100算力的60%，但功耗高出H100的40%。</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://heninswift.github.io/heninma.github.io/post/Report%20by%20COPU%20Honorary%20Chairman%20Lu%20Shouqun%20at%20the%2020th%20Open%20Source%20China%20Open%20Source%20World%20Conference.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 02:26:39 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>